

# **Contact information**

- Tropavænget 38, Næstved 4700,Denmark
- 71882266
- ramu0225@gmail.com
  Portfolio
  Codepen
  Github

#### **Personal Info**

I am a self-motivated, dedicated, fun, outgoing, sports persons, like to make friends. In free time like to spend time with my family & friends. My hobbies are playing cricket, football and indoor games.

#### **IT Skills**

HTML5, CSS/Sass, JavaScript, React(JSX), Redux, Wordpress, NodeJs, firebase, Bootstrap, RestAPIs, Git, VS-code.

#### Certification

Responsive Web Design.
JavaScript & Data Structures
Front End Libraries

#### Languages

Telugu: Mother tongue

Hindi : Native English : Fluent Danish : Basic level

Nationality: Indian DOB: 05/08/1980

### **Professional Profile**

Currently I am looking for a position in front-end developer, as i am passionate about programming & have many years of professional experience in the field of engineering and various SW/HW technologies. I have strong technical skills as well as excellent analytical abilities & good communication skills, enabling me to interact with a wide range of clients. I am eager to be challenged in order to grow & improve my IT skills.

# **Work Experience**

## Freelance Developer

#### 2019 - Present

- Creating new features, functionality and capabilities on the e-Commerce sites using JavaScript/JSX, Ajax, SASS and JSON.
- Developed app integration with REST API, social media logins, payment processors, and other services.
- Designing and implementing HTML email templates and newsletters for marketing campaigns.

Front-End Engineer | DFD A/S, St.heddinge, Denmark

2012 - 2019

**Project Engineer | Bharat Electronic Limited**, *Hyderabad*,

*India.* 2003 - 2007

# **Education**

M.S in System-on-Chip | Lund University, Sweden.

2007 - 2010

B.Tech in Electronics & Communication | AEC, Hyderabad,

*India.* 1999 – 2003